A Guide to the Ruritan National records, 1928-1963
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Ruritan National records, 1928-1963
The Library of Virginia
24763
1.35 cu. ft.; 4 boxes
Ruritan National
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gifts of Thomas V. Downing, Franktown, Virginia (24763 and 25816) and Ruritan Nationa, Wakefield, Virginia (25341).
Biographical Information
The first club was organized in 1928 in Holland, Nansemond County, Virginia, as a rural civic club which was concerned with the problems of the farming community, including agriculture, education, church, youth, etc., and included farmers, as well as business and professional members. Ruritan National was organized in April 1930 and held its first national convention in Suffolk Virginia on 15 January 1932.
Scope and Content
Records, 1928-1963, of the Ruritan National organization, consisting of records, 1928-1958, containing the minutes of the National Board of Directors, 1930-1958 (1 v.); minutes of national conventions, 1933-1958, with a program for the first national convention held in 1932 in Suffolk, Virginia (1 v.); and correspondence, telegrams, committee reports, and newspaper clippings, 1928-1950 (1 v.). Contains 1000 forms with name and occupation of charter members and officers of Ruritan clubs (with charter numbers) in the United States., as well as the location and date the club was chartered, and includes an alphabetical index of club names in the front of each volume. Also contains records 1928-1963, consisting of biographical sketches, bylaws, and charter applications of Ruritan National, Holland Ruritan Club, and Ivor Ruritan Club (1928-1963); Ruritan National convention programs (1932-1957) and district convention programs (1936-1956).
Contents List
- Accession 24763 records, 1928-1958., Extent: 1 box.
  - Minutes of national board of directors, 1930-1958. (Box 24763, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of national convention, 1932-1958. (Box 24763, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, telegrams, committee reports, 1928-1950. (Box 24763, Folder 3)
- Accession 25341 charter lists, 1928-1960., Extent: 2 boxes
  - Charter list, 1-100. (Box 25341, Box 1)
  - Charter list, 101-200. (Box 25341, Box 1)
  - Charter list, 201-300. (Box 25341, Box 1)
  - Charter list, 301-400. (Box 25341, Box 1)
  - Charter list, 401-500. (Box 25341, Box 1)
  - Charter list, 501-600. (Box 25341, Box 2)
  - Charter list, 601-700. (Box 25341, Box 2)
  - Charter list, 701-800. (Box 25341, Box 2)
  - Charter list, 801-900. (Box 25341, Box 2)
  - Charter list, 901-1000. (Box 25341, Box 2)
- Accession 25816 records, 1928-1963., Extent: 1 box
  - Histories and by-laws, 1928-1963. (Box 25816, Folder 1)
  - National convention programs, 1932-1957. (Box 25816, Folder 2)
  - District convention programs, 1936-1956. (Box 25816, Folder 3)